Guide to the Rufus King Papers, 1766-1899, (bulk, 1783-1826) MS 1660
New-York Historical Society
- Box 26- Francisco de Miranda Correspondence, Francisco de Miranda material has been microfilmed on Miscellaneous Microfilm Reel #81. Some material in this box was rehoused from a box entitled "Box A." A short calendar of the letters is included in the beginning of the box.
  - Letters to and from Francisco de Miranda, 1805-1806 (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Box 27- Notes and Drafts, Items in folders 5 and 6 have not been item-level catalogued. Some material in this box was rehoused from a box labeled "Box A."
  - Notes and correspondence re Letters by Rufus King (including correspondence of Charles R. King), 1893-1896 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Notes on England and War, [1803] (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Notes on Louisiana, 1803, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Notes on Massachusetts Ratifying Convention, 1788 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Notes and Drafts on Various Topics including Pirates, Navigation, and Commerce, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Notes and Drafts on Various Topics including Contraband, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Notes and Drafts on Various Topics including Louisiana Treaty and the French Revolution, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Notes and on Various Topics including Senate Proceedings, [1790-1799] (Box 27, Folder 8)
- Volume 28- Letterbook, This volume is on microfilm.
  - Letterbook, Letters to Rufus King from Alexander Hamilton, 1787-1799 (Volume 28)
- Box 29- Joseph Pitcairn Letters
  - Letters to Rufus King from Joseph Pitcairn, 1796-1797 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Rufus King from Joseph Pitcairn, 1798 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Letters to Rufus King from Joseph Pitcairn, 1799 Jan.-1799 Mar. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Rufus King from Joseph Pitcairn, 1799 Apr.-1799 May (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Rufus King from Joseph Pitcairn, 1799 June-1799 Aug. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Rufus King from Joseph Pitcairn, 1799 Sept.-1799 Dec. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Rufus King from Joseph Pitcairn, 1800 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Rufus King from Joseph Pitcairn, 1801 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Letters to Rufus King from Joseph Pitcairn, 1802 (Box 29, Folder 9)
- Box 30- Rufus King and Others' Correspondence, The documents in this box were previously numbered and catalogued at the item level. They are arranged according to those numbers and not chronologically.
  - Letters to and from Rufus King and Others, 1801-1803 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King and Others, 1799-1803 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King and Others, 1799-1803 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King and Others, 1801-1803 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King and Others, 1796-1801 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Letters to and from Rufus King and Others, 1799-1801 (Box 30, Folder 6)
- Volume 31- Letterbook, This volume is on microfilm.
  - Letterbook, American Political Letters to Rufus King, 1800-1802 (Volume 31)
- Volume 32- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, American Letters on Public and Private Business to Rufus King, 1796-1802 (Volume 32)
- Volume 33- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, American Letters of Introduction to Rufus King, 1796-1802 (Volume 33)
- Volume 34- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Letters from Bird, Savage, & Bird (Bankers of the U.S., London) to Rufus King containing Communications on Public and Private Business, 1796-1803 (Volume 34)
- Volume 35- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Letters from American Consuls and Agents for Seamen Resident of Great Britain and Ireland to Rufus King, 1796-1803 (Volume 35)
- Volume 36- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Letters from American Consuls Residing on the Continents of Europe and Africa to Rufus King, also letters regarding Barbary Affairs, 1796-1803 (Volume 36)
- Volume 37- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Letters and Accounts of Nicholas Low as the Agent of Rufus King, 1796-1802 (Volume 37)
- Volume 38- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, American Private Letters to Rufus King, 1796-1802 (Volume 38)
- Volume 39- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Letters from John and Francis Baring & Co. and Francis Baring & Co., 1796-1803 (Volume 39)
- Volume 40- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Commission under the Sixth Article of the American Treaty, 1794, Cases and Proceedings, 1798-1799 (Volume 40)
- Volume 41- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, American Political Letters to Rufus King, 1796-1799 (Volume 41)
- Volume 42- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Commission under the Sixth Article of the American Treaty 1794, Correspondence and Instructions, 1799 (Volume 42)
- Volume 43- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Letters and Communications from the American Agents and Commissioners acting under the Treaty of Amity Commerce and Navigation between Great Britain and the United States, 1796-1803 (Volume 43)
- Volume 44- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Sundry Statements respecting Articles of the American Treaty, 1794, 1799-1801 (Volume 44)
- Volume 45- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Letters from Thomas Pickering (Secretary of State of the US) to Rufus King, 1796-1800 (Volume 45)
- Volume 46- Letterbook, This volume is on microfilm.
  - Letterbook, Negotiations of John Jay Containing Correspondence Relative to the Treaty of Amity, Commerce, and Navigation, 1794 (Volume 46)
- Volume 47- Letterbook, This volume is on microfilm filed under Troup, Robert.
  - Letterbook, Letters from Col. Robert Troup to Rufus King, 1796-1802 (Volume 47)
- Volume 48- Letterbook, This volume is on microfilm.
  - Letterbook, Letters from Thomas Pickney and William Allen Deas to the American Secretary of State (Vol. I), 1792-1796 (Volume 48)
- Volume 49- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Letters from Thomas Pickney and William Allen Deas to Lord Grenville (Vol. II), 1792-1796 (Volume 49)
- Volume 50- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Letters from Lord Greenville to Thomas Pickney and William Allen Deas, 1792-1796 (Volume 50)
- Volume 51- Letterbook, This volume is on microfilm.
  - Letterbook, Letters to and from Rufus King, 1796-1797 (Volume 51)
- Volume 52- Letterbook, This volume is on microfilm.
  - Letterbook, Letters from Rufus King (includes enclosures of letters to Rufus King), 1798 (Volume 52)
- Volume 53- Letterbook, This volume is on microfilm.
  - Letterbook, Letters from Rufus King (includes enclosures of letters to Rufus King), 1799-1800 (Volume 53)
- Volume 54- Letterbook, This volume is on microfilm filed under Marshall, John.
  - Letterbook, Letters from Rufus King (includes enclosures of letters to Rufus King), 1801 (Volume 54)
- Volume 55- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Letters to and from Rufus King, 1802-1803 (Volume 55)
- Volume 56- Notebook, This volume is on microfilm.
  - Notebook, Papers relating to War Between Great Britain and Spain in 1739, Maritime Cases, obtained by Rufus King, undated (Volume 56)
- Volume 57- Notebook
  - Notebook, Notes and Daily Entries on Writings of Washington, Jefferson, and John Jay, 1830, undated (Volume 57)
- Volume 58- Notebook, This volume is on microfilm.
  - Notebook, Rufus King Political Essay on Spanish America (in French), 1792-1793 (Volume 58)
- Volume 59- Notebook, This volume is on microfilm.
  - Notebook, Rufus King Political Essay on Peace in the Next Century (in French), 1797 (Volume 59)
- Volume 60- Notebook, This volume is on microfilm.
  - Notebook, Rufus King Political Essay on Spanish Subject (in French), undated (Volume 60)
- Volume 61- Notebook, This volume is on microfilm.
  - Notebook, Rufus King Political Essay on Peace in the Next Century (in French), undated (Volume 61)
- Volume 62- Notebook, This volume is on microfilm.
  - Notebook, Rufus King Political Essay on South American Independence (in French), 1790-1795 (Volume 62)
- Volume 63- Letterbook
  - Letterbook "A," Letters from Rufus King, 1796 July 24-1798 June 30 (Volume 63)
- Volume 64- Letterbook
  - Letterbook "B," Letters from Rufus King, 1798 July 2-1799 May 27 (Volume 64)
- Volume 65- Letterbook
  - Letterbook "C," Letters from Rufus King, 1799 May 31- 1800 Dec. 28 (Volume 65)
- Volume 66- Letterbook
  - Letterbook "D," Letters from Rufus King, 1801 Jan. 3-1801 Dec. 31 (Volume 66)
- Volume 67- Letterbook
  - Letterbook "E," Letters from Rufus King, 1802 Jan. 8-1803 Apr. 12 (Volume 67)
- Volume 68- Miscellaneous Acts of the Governor
  - Miscellaneous Acts of the Governor (John Alsop King, Governor of New York), 1857 Jan.- 1858 Dec. (Volume 68)
- Volume 69- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Letters to and from Rufus King and John Alsop, 1786-1796 (Volume 69)
- Volume 70- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Abstract of Letters to Rufus King from the Secretary of State, 1796-1803 (Volume 70)
- Volume 71- Letterbook
  - Letterbooks, Abstract of Letters from Rufus King to the Secretary of State and others, 1796-1799 (Volume 71)
- Volume 72- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Abstract of Letters from Rufus King to the Secretary of State, 1799-1803 (Volume 72)
- Volume 73- Notebook, This volume is on microfilm.
  - Notebook, Rufus King Memoranda and Reflections about Contemporary People and Events, 1794-1801 (Volume 73)
    Scope and Contents
    This volume includes King's memorandum dated May 3, 1797, of his conversation with Benjamin West, which includes West's statement that King George had thought Washington to be "the greatest character of the age."
- Volume 74- Notebook
  - Notebook, Inventory of Rufus King Library, 1827 (Volume 74)
- Volume 74A- Notebook
  - Notebook, Inventory of Rufus King Library, undated (Volume 74A)
- Volume 75- Notebook
  - Notebook, Notes on History and Current Events in France and England, 1803 (Volume 75)
- Volume 76- Notebook
  - Notebook, Notes on History and Current Events such as Currency, Fisheries, Florida, etc., 1801-1802 (Volume 76)
- Volume 77- Notebook
  - Notebook, Notes on Ordinance of Western Territory, US and French Treaty- Includes later memoranda from Charles King on Rufus King's career, [1803, 1894-1899] (Volume 77)
- Volume 78- Notebook
  - Notebook, Notes on Journey in Europe, 1802 (Volume 78)
- Volume 79- Notebook
  - Notebook, Notes on Current Events in France, England, Russia, etc., 1799-1802 (Volume 79)
- Box 80- Rufus King and John Trumbull Correspondence
  - Letters between Rufus King and John Trumbull, 1809-1822 (Box 80, Folder 1)
- Box 81- Notes and Correspondence, The Viscardo y Guzman material in folder 15 is on microfilm.
  - Notes on Powers of Government, Brief of "Missouri Speech," Notes on Slavery and Statehood, 1819-1822, undated (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Notes including "Abolition Treaty between Great Britain and Spain" of Sept. 23, 1817 and notes on events of 1776, undated (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Notes on Fisheries, Indian Territories, and on Spain, France, and Louisiana, 1809-1814, undated (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Abstract of Report of a Committee of the Privy Council, 1791 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Representation in Senate and House of Representatives, Examination of Order in Council by French Decree, 1808, undated (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Notes on Admission of New States, [1791-1819] (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence re Rufus King's Death, Notes re Jay Treaty and Negotiation before the Peace of 1763, 1783-1824, 1894 (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Notes on Bankrupt Bill, Notes on European Intervention between Spain and its Revolted Colonies, 1820, undated (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Will and Documents of John Alsop, 1788 (Box 81, Folder 9)
  - Memorandum concerning "The Propagation of Trees and Shrubs", 1806 (Box 81, Folder 10)
  - Notes and Drafts, undated (Box 81, Folder 11)
  - Article "Rufus King and the Missouri Compromise" from the New York Enquirer, 1848 (Box 81, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1813-1865 (Box 81, Folder 13)
  - Sketches of Newspaper Articles, 1804 (Box 81, Folder 14)
  - Letters and Manuscript of Juan Pablo Viscardo y Guzman (in French), 1782 (Box 81, Folder 15)
  - Transcriptions of Letters of Rufus King, 1817-1825 (Box 81, Folder 16)
  - Transcriptions of Letters of Rufus King and Letters to John A. King and Charles R. King, [1799-1825], 1895-1899 (Box 81, Folder 17)
  - Receipts and Clippings of Signatures, 1778-1826 (Box 81, Folder 18)
- Box 82- Rufus King and Henry Clay Correspondence
  - Letters from Rufus King to Henry Clay, 1825 Aug.-1825 Sept. (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Letters from Rufus King to Henry Clay, 1825 Oct.-1825 Dec. (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Letters from Rufus King to Henry Clay, 1826 Jan.-1826 June (Box 82, Folder 3)
- Box 83- Rufus King and George Canning Correspondence
  - Letters from Rufus King to George Canning, 1825 Aug.-1825 Dec. (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Letters from Rufus King to George Canning, 1826 Jan.-1826 June (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Letters from George Canning to Rufus King, 1825 Aug.-1826 Apr. (Box 83, Folder 3)
- Box 84- Rufus King Correspondence
  - Letters to and from Rufus King, re Post as Minister Plenipotentiary including Commission and Resignation letter, 1824-1826 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Letters and Drafts of Letters to Rufus King, Documents re Elizabeth Hamilton vs. Rufus King and Nicholas Fish, 1825-1826 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Letters and Copies of Letters to and from Rufus King, includes Documents re Objections of Peter Morgan over a Bill and Letter re Georgia Boundaries, 1763-1897 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Various Documents including Committee for the Plan of Western Territory, Committee for Secrecy, List of Property Taken by British, 1775-1853 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Letters of Rufus King to Oliver Wolcott, 1796-1808 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Documents re West Florida, 1763-1770 (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Passport of John A. King, 1826 (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - Commissions of Rufus King and John A. King to Great Britain, 1796-1825 (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - Oversized appointments, commissions, and other documents issued to Rufus and John Alsop King. 15 items., 1796-1825 (Oversize Small)
    Access Restrictions
    Contains presidential signatures, among them George Washington and John Adams.
- Box 85- Maps and Correspondence
  - Map of Florida, Published Correspondence with Great Britain re Island of Abaco, Statement re Lighthouse, 1824 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Letters Including Instructions to Rufus King in Great Britain from Henry Clay, 1825 (Box 85, Folder 2)
- Box 86- Papers re East India Trade, no content
  - Papers re East India Trade, 1796-1797 (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Papers re East India Trade, 1879, 1803 (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Papers re East India Trade, 1895 (Box 86, Folder 3)
- Box 87- Rufus King and John Laurance Correspondence, These materials are on microfilm.
  - Letters of Rufus King to John Laurance, 1793-1799 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Deed of Partition of Rufus King to John Laurance, 1808 (Box 87, Folder 2)
- Box 88- Granville Sharpe Correspondence, no content
  - "Sundry Letters and Papers" from Granville Sharpe, 1784-1797 (Box 88, Folder 1)
- Box 89- Charles King Correspondence
  - Letters to and from Charles R. King re Letters between Rufus King and Alexander Hamilton, 1894 Apr.-1895 Apr. (Box 89, Folder 1)
- Box 90- Materials of Rufus King, John A. King, and Mary King, The material in this box came from an envelope previously labeled, "Misc. Mss."
  - Receipts of John A. King and Mary King, 1865-1870 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Notes and Letters of Rufus King, undated (Box 90, Folder 2)
- Box 91- Beer's Long Island Almanac
  - Beer's Long Island Almanac, 1823, 1824 (Box 91, Folder 1)
- Box 92- Newspapers of Rufus King/ Report on Repeal of Fugitive Slave Acts, no content
  - Newspapers Owned by Rufus King, undated (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Newspapers Owned by Rufus King, 1796-1801 (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Newspapers Owned by Rufus King, 1802-1820 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers Owned by Rufus King, 1821-1823 (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Newspapers Owned by Rufus King, 1824-1848 (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Report and Minority Report on Repeal of Fugitive Slave Acts, 1864 (Box 92, Folder 6)
- Volume 93- Book of Houses and Stables
  - Book of Houses Rented and Stable Expenses, 1783-1795 (Volume 93)
- Volume 94- Letterbook
  - Letterbook, Private Letters from Rufus King, 1796-1803 (Volume 94)
- Volume 95- Memorandum of Letters
  - Memorandum of Private Letters, 1796-1802 (Volume 95)
- Volume 96- Memorandum of Letters
  - Memorandum of Private Letters, 1802-1803 (Volume 96)
- Volume 97- Account Book
  - Account Book, Private and US Accounts with Bird, Savage & Bird, 1796-1803 (Volume 97)
- Volume 98- Memorandum Book
  - Memorandum Book, includes Account Information, 1796-1801 (Volume 98)
- Volume 99- Memorandum of Letters
  - Memorandum of Letters, includes diaries entries for 1803, 1803-1806 (Volume 99)
- Volume 100- Account book
  - Account book, Household Accounts, 1806-1825 (Volume 100)
- Volume 101- Notebook
  - Notebook, Notes on England and Philosophy of Government, 1820 (Volume 101)
- Volume 102- Notebook
  - Notebook, James King's Notes on Historian Edward Gibbon, 1799 (Volume 102)
- Volume 103- Notebook
  - Notebook, Descriptions of Prominent English Physicians, undated (Volume 103)
- Volume 104- Scrapbook
  - Scrapbook of Newspaper Articles, 1787-1818 (Volume 104)
- Volume 105- Notebook
  - Notebook, Notes on State Charters, undated (Volume 105)